Kenny Fernsten



kfernsten@gmail.com



8013724349



linkedin.com/in/kennyfern

Summary

Software Engineer with a strong emphasis on user experiences and front-end development.

I have worked in various back-end, and front-end technologies and frameworks. I adapt quickly and learn new technologies as needed. I love providing users with an easy-to-use experience with coherent feedback during their experience while meeting business requirements and timelines. I enjoy working with designers to bridge the gap between development and design.

Experience

cricut. Architect/Staff Software (Angular) Engineer

Cricut

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 10 months)

- Introduced, built, and defined internal design system and component library. Worked closely with UI counterparts to audit, propose, and build new components defined by UI in Angular. Introduced Storybook to document components for designers and developers. Researched and built components with full accessibility in mind, including keyboard navigation, contrast ratios, and screen reader information. Created and tested components to work in right-to-left languages. Utilized Chromatic to add visual regression testing for the component library.
- Built various scripts to treat Figma as the source of truth for design system artifacts (colors, icons, typography). Allowing desktop, iOS, and Android platforms to use abstracted design tokens on their platforms.
- Built automation tooling around internationalization (i18n) workflow. Allowing individual teams/pods to be more autonomous.
- Architected distributed frameworks for pods to be able to work independently of the main bundling application and other pods.
- Assisted in defining and overseeing migration from a single monorepo to distributed pod repo structure.

cricut. Senior Software (Angular) Engineer

Cricut

Apr 2016 - Dec 2021 (5 years 9 months)

- Introduced, built, defined, and managed the internationalization (i18n) process and migration for the entire desktop application.
- Introduced, defined, and built an interactive tutorial system. Allowing developers to define a custom tutorial and have the framework dynamically highlight elements for users to interact with and to progress the tutorial.

- Created curved text feature. Required working with custom drawing framework to overcome rendering issues to ensure a 60 fps experience for users.
- Managed, taught, and coached interns with writing unit-test coverage for the application.
- Introduced and built the initial unit tests for the application and created consistent patterns for other developers to follow.

Tech Lead, Senior UI/UX Developer

Western Governors University

Sep 2013 - Apr 2016 (2 years 8 months)

- Hired as the first UI developer on a new UI team. Tasked with making the front-end an easier ecosystem to develop and deploy code. Made the experience more consistent and stable for the students using the product.
- Introduced and built global processes for AngularJS, Sass, and GruntJS.
- Created a Sass-centric CSS framework with reusable components to achieve a consistent brand and experience for students.
- Rebuilt student portal with upgraded front-end and architecture. Orchestrated the upgrade, testing, and deployment of several applications at the same time with minimal impact on the students.
- Developed code standards and code review practices to achieve a consistent ecosystem.
- Directed, mentored, and trained other programmers.

C Front-end Web Developer

Clearlink

Apr 2012 - Sep 2013 (1 year 6 months)

- Created and maintained several sites used to drive traffic for affiliate leads and sales. Front-end heavy workload with PHP and MySQL used for the back-end of projects.

BYU Web Developer

Brigham Young University

Oct 2010 - Apr 2012 (1 year 7 months)

Developed various web applications for use by 40+ faculty. Collaborated with several people to produce finished products. Used Django, PostgreSQL, and PHP for building applications.

Education

BYU Brigham Young University

BS, Information Technology 2008 - 2012